Collin Whalen

Front-End Developer

Saint Paul, MN (612) 517-6792 whalencollin@gmail.com

PROJECTS

Capital Opulence — A personal finance application

This application allows a user to create an account then begin tracking daily financial gains and expenses. Data entered by the user is rendered as a bar graph and stored in the user's dashboard.

https://capital-opulence.herokuapp.com/

Mantis Mocha — A coffee e-commerce site

Mantis Mocha is built with the MERN stack and the Stripe payment API. A fast and customizable user experience was a top priority when developing this application. https://mantismocha.herokuapp.com/

Movie Finder — Discover and watch thousands of movies

A front-end JavaScript application that utilizes two movie APIs. Movie Finder helps a user quickly find their next movie and where they can pay to watch it, based on genre. https://cassie-s.github.io/movie-finder/

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota coding boot camp, — Web development

July 2021 - Feb 2022

A rigorous 24-week program focused on gaining proficient technical programming skills essential for front and back-end website development.

Century College, Mahtomedi — *Nursing prerequisites/ generals*

Aug 2019 - May 2021

EXPERIENCE

Punch Neapolitan Pizza, Roseville — *Cook*

Aug 2019 - Present

- Working as a team.
- Communicating with 100+ customers a shift.
- Satisfying custom orders while staying attentive to detail.
- Training new employees, our restaurant procedures, how to cook, prepare ingredients, and communicate during peak hours.

Chipotle, Vadnais Heights — *Cook*

Jan 2016 - June 2018

- Completing work in a fast and high-pressure environment.
- Remaining flexible in a changing, unpredictable environment.
- Arriving early to every shift and completing duties in a timely manner.
- Training new employees in any crew member position.

SKILLS

JavaScript

MERN Full Stack

(MongoDB, Express,

React, Node)

HTML

CSS and CSS frameworks

jQuery

RESTful APIs

JSON (JavaScript Object

Notation)

MySQL

NoSQL

OOP

SCRUM Agile

Development

Git and GitHub

Visual Studio Code

SEO (Search Engine

Optimization)

XML

REST (Representational

State Transfer)

Responsive Web Design

Leadership

Communication

PROFESSIONAL LINKS

Portfolio:

https://collin-w.github.io/prof

essional-portfolio/

GitHub:

https://github.com/Collin-W

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/c

ollin-whalen/

CERTIFICATIONS

U of M Bootcamp Completion Badge